Now in contrast, alpha factors are,
Alpha 因子
generally speaking, not yet well known by the majority of the investment community.
通常并不为大部分投资者所熟知
The community's limited awareness of an alpha factor also affects how it can be used,
由于投资圈子不太知道某个 alpha 因子 那么这个因子的用途也会不同
because those who generate and use proprietary alpha factors can use them to
因创建和使用专有 alpha 因子的投资者
potentially seek a competitive edge in generating better than average performance.
能够把握竞争优势 并获得比平均业绩更高的业绩
Let's say we find an alpha factor defined as
假设我们找到一个 alpha 因子
the maximum single day return over the past month.
它与过去一个月最高单日收益率有关
According to the hypothesis of this alpha factor,
根据此 alpha 因子的假设
the higher the single day maximum return in a recent window of time,
在最近一段时间内 单日最高收益率越高
the more likely the stock will have a lower return in the near future.
股票在最近的未来越有可能收益率更低
We'll examine this alpha factor in a later lesson.
我们将在后面的课程中介绍这个 alpha 因子
For now, just assume that we have an alpha factor that
暂时假设我们有一个 alpha 因子
gives us an indication of the future price movements of the stock.
能够告诉我们股票未来的股价变化
Also assume that most others in the investment community are not yet using this factor.
并且假设大部分其他投资者还没有使用此因子
So, if we see a stock exhibit a high single day maximum in a recent window of time,
所以 如果我们看到股票在最近一段时间内出现很高的单日最高收益率
we may decide to trade based on that signal,
我们可能会根据该信号进行交易
expecting the stock to have lower returns in the near future.
预计该股票在最近的未来收益率更低
Since others are not doing the same as we are,
因为其他人没有这么做
this alpha factor essentially gives us
所以这个 alpha 因子使我们能够
the potential opportunity to act on that signal before others do,
根据该信号 快人一步发现潜在机会
thereby helping us in our quest to seek better than average performance.
从而帮助我们获得高于平均业绩的业绩
Since alpha factors can potentially help an investor seek better than average returns,
因为 alpha 因子能帮助投资者获得高于平均值的收益
then we also say that alpha factors are drivers of the mean of portfolio return.
所以 alpha 因子是投资组合收益均值的推动因素
This is because alpha factors can help push the portfolio return in a certain direction.
这是因为 alpha 因子能够帮助推动投资组合收益朝着特定的方向发展
We can think of this as a sail boat on the ocean.
可以将其看作在海上行驶的帆船
If the boat had sails,
如果船有帆
then the boat could make prudent use of the winds to
那么船可以有效利用风力
push the boat's average position in a desired direction.
使船的平均位置朝着目标方向移动
Similarly, if the investor makes effective use of alpha factors,
同理 如果投资者有效利用 alpha 因子
they can use those alpha factors to drive
那么他们能够推动
the mean of the portfolio return in a certain direction,
投资组合收益的均值朝着特定方向变化
ideally in an upward direction.
最好是上涨方向